She has depression.
It's true. She is my wife.
She's your wife?
Yes, Man of God. It's true.
From where?
We came from the United States.
The United States?
Yes.
She has depression and she has suicidal thoughts.
It's true.
Having received a prophecy about the spirit of depression and suicidal thoughts,
this woman is delivered in the power of the Holy Ghost.
Emmanuel!
Good Morning!
My name is Thania Requeno and I'm from the United States.
This is my husband Akeem Jequeno.
This is my elder brother, Minor
and this is my sister in Christ, Elena.
This is my baby, Caleb.
What brought me to The Synagogue Church Of All Nations was that I was seeking deliverance,
seeking breakthrough from stagnation and for my career.
We were here on January 1st for the New Year Service.
When the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua was ministering, he laid hands on me
and I manifested.
I didn't really know what happened. I saw myself on the floor.
He had prophesied about a spirit of depression and suicidal thoughts.
When I reflect back on that, I can see how the spirit was attacking me.
I am more of a people person and
there would be some times where I would just want to run away from people,
from my family and after I got married, even from my husband.
I would isolate myself and go to places.
Sometimes I would just take my car and drive somewhere and park somewhere and cry.
Sometimes, I would go into the bathroom, turn the shower on and just cry in the shower.
I had this deep sorrow in my heart and I didn't really understand why
because I was born again three years ago and
my inner spirit would tell me that I was saved, that I believed in Jesus Christ.
But I still felt this pain, this sorrow, this very deep sorrow -
I don't know how to explain it - in my heart.
I would come out of it.
Sometimes I would argue with my husband but then I would come out of it and
then I would come back to him and apologise.
We would even joke about it.
He would joke about it with me - 'one moment, you're sad and the next moment, you are happy',
We would joke about it but in all honesty, it was something serious.
So, when the man of God laid hands on me and he spoke that, it made a lot of sense to me
and I understood that all those episodes I had were really attacks from the enemy.
I also remembered that when I came to Christ three years ago,
I had this supernatural joy over my life that even unbelievers would testify to.
They would ask me, 'Are you high right now? Are you drunk? Why are you so happy?'
I would testify and tell them that it was Jesus Christ. I would preach the Gospel.
Anywhere I went, people would notice that - believers, unbelievers and my family.
Somehow along the way, that joy left me.
And so, when the man of God laid hands on me, I know that the joy came back to me.
I just thank God because I want to testify that Jesus Christ is Lord and
tell people that there is hope and they don't have to suffer from depression,
that these are just spiritual things, not physical.
They are spiritual things that everybody goes through but not everybody knows the solution.
I just want to thank the Lord for The SCOAN and for the favour and grace over my life,
over my family's life, over the prophet and over The SCOAN
because there has just been so much favour since we came on January 1st this year
and I am excited to go home tomorrow and taste the goodness of the Lord
and just to walk with Him.
Indeed words of the mouth are not enough to really express deeply
what the Lord has done in your life, other than to say, 'Thank You, Jesus Christ'.
Let's put our hands together beautifully for the miracle working God!
We thank God Almighty for what He has done in your life.
In other words, you are making us to realise that initially you came purposely because
you wanted financial breakthrough - that was what you came for.
And all of a sudden the Spirit of God went into areas that were really troubling your life
but you never took seriously. Is that correct?
That is correct.
Like I said, I came for breakthrough from stagnation in my life
and for my career because I always saw a pattern in those things.
But the Bible says that God searches the depths of our hearts
and I know that was what He did that day
because I was not expecting to have received that word.
I wanted to receive something about my career - the stagnation again but
the root of my problems with stagnation and in my career was actually depression
and suicidal thoughts.
I could continue and get breakthrough in my career but then not get delivered from depression
and I wouldn't be able to enjoy that or testify to the goodness of the Lord
and so I'm just thankful again for the word that I received, for the prophecy
and for the deliverance.
Amen.
Thank You, Jesus.
Ever since the prophecy came to pass in your life and you were delivered,
are you still having depression or suicidal thoughts?
What can you say about the state of your mind and your entire body right now?
I do not feel any depression. I have no suicidal thoughts.
I can feel the genuine joy in my spirit ever since
the prophet laid hands on me.
The following day, we also went for prayer and I felt something leave my heart again
and I know that the joy is going to keep coming and coming and I'll be able to
share the Gospel and share Jesus Christ with everyone.
I'm thankful for that.
Shall we put our hands together beautifully for the miracle working God.
We rejoice with you greatly.
Before we hear from you a word of advice for all and sundry,
we just want to hear from your husband.
Could you just introduce yourself to us and tell us your own side of the story.
Good Morning Church!
Emmanuel!
My name is Akeem Jequenu.
I am from Benin Republic but I reside in the United States.
This is my wife Thania. That's my brother-in-law, Minor and that's my sister in Christ, Elena.
Concerning the prophecy, the word that she received from the man of God is true.
When I first got married to her, it was something that she would hide from people. People didn't know.
But being alone in the house with her, I understood that something was going on in her life
because one moment she would be happy and the next moment, she would be very very sad.
She would hide and cry. Sometimes I would surprise her when she was crying.
Then she would make comments like, 'I just feel like going somewhere and drinking'.
So, I knew it wasn't normal.
Being a believer in our Lord Jesus Christ, we went to some churches and a lot of places in the US.
Those big names in the Gospel in the US, we went there seeking help for this trouble.
But we couldn't find anybody to help.
I remembered my experience with the Lord a little before I met her.
When I was still in Africa, people used to talk about Prophet T.B. Joshua
but for me, I concluded he was not a man of God because of the things I heard from people.
Also he's not a sweet-talker.
I listened to him one or two times and asked myself, "Who goes and sits down in his church?
What do they do there?"
I didn't really believe he was a man of God.
But then, when I was in the US, I went through some tough times,
some very rough times, moments of my life.
One day I was in New York and I went to one of these mega churches for someone to pray with me.
The white lady who was praying with me asked me where I was from.
I said I was from Benin Republic and she said, 'Do you know T.B. Joshua? That's very close to your nation'.
I said, 'Yes I know T.B. Joshua'.
And she started talking about how beautiful his ministry is and
how there were deliverance and family reconciliations, helping the poor and scholarships for the needy.
And I was like, 'This T.B. Joshua is everywhere. Why is everybody always talking about T.B. Joshua?'
Mr & Mrs Thania Requeno - Prophecy Testimony
It's true that I didn't say anything bad about him but in my heart, I knew that he was not a man of God.
So, later on, I went on a fast because things were going terribly for me,
I was going through difficult times and hardship.
I went on a fast for 21 days, just to seek the face of God about my situation and my life.
And then on the fifth day of my fast, I had a vision early in the morning.
In this vision, I saw the Lord Jesus Christ in one corner and then I wasn't happy, I was going towards Him.
But He was pointing in the opposite direction.
And then I turned back to see and there was Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Mr & Mrs Thania Requeno & Family - Prophecy Testimony
Still in that moment in the vision, I still convinced myself that, 'This is not a man of God!'
So I looked at him and I turned back. I was walking to the Lord Jesus Christ
and He said, 'No, go to him'.
So I turned back and I went to Prophet T.B. Joshua and the most amazing spiritual experience of my life
happened that day.
Because he was reading my mind and telling me everything that I needed to know
and teaching me great teachings that day,
Even from that experience only, I can testify that he is a man of God
because there was no way he could know all those things deep in my heart that he told me.
After that he told me, 'I have been appointed to take care of you'.
And I said, 'Does that mean that you are my spiritual father?" And he said, 'Yes'.
And I said, 'Does that mean that I will walk in the same element as my dad?'
And he said, 'Yes' and started laughing.
I remembered in the vision that I didn't have my documents yet to leave the country and come back.
I was going to say, 'Pray for me so I can go to The SCOAN. I want to come now.'
And he was smiling as if it was already done and then I came out of that vision.
Later on, I went online and listened to his preaching.
And I saw that it is true that he doesn't give motivational speeches but he speaks from the Spirit of God.
Mr & Mrs Thania Requeno & Family - Prophecy Testimony
That is not enough for Jesus Christ. Put your hands together beautifully for the miracle working God!
And I also saw other sides to the ministry and I believe that people in my position then, didn't know that he was doing all these things.
But from one blackmail to another, people make up their minds that he is not a man of God.
I sent someone to The SCOAN, saying, 'Get me the Anointing Water, the Sticker and everything you can get'.
So my friend came here to Nigeria and he sent everything to me.
I was able to file for residency in the US and I sprinkled and I prayed; I started following him.
One night, I was listening to the Mass Prayer, the one that he does with viewers all over the world.
And I was convinced that night.
I asked myself, 'Why wouldn't I think that this was a man of God?"
Because everything that comes from his mouth is from God.
A kingdom divided against itself cannot prosper - that's what the Bible says.
If this man is of the devil, why is he casting out devils?
So, it is not possible that he does all these things if he's not from God.
Mr & Mrs Thania Requeno & Family - Prophecy Testimony
So I told my wife and my brother-in-law, 'This is the experience I have had with this man of God in Africa'.
I said, 'We are going to go there as soon as I get my documents' and that's what we did.
When I got my green card, my brother-in-law told me, 'What are we waiting for?' Let's go now'.
So, we got our tickets and then we just came here.
And when you finally came to The SCOAN, could you just reflect on what happened to your wife
and the state of her mind after the prophecy and deliverance.
How can you confirm that to be true?
I confirm the prophecy to be true.
He's somebody who doesn't live with us.
If we had filed everything and talked about depression before we came here,
maybe we would doubt and think that this man just read what we had sent via email and said something.
But we didn't file anything; we just came on our own and sat at the back there.
And he came and directly pointed at the issue.
He said, 'Depression and suicidal thoughts'.
How in the world would you know that if it was not the Lord who told you?
Ever since he prayed for her, she is delivered.
Now, she's happy; even I am happy.
I used to be so frustrated. My wife would always be happy and then sad. It was on my neck.
But now, she is free and we are all a very beautiful and happy family.
Shall we put our hands together beautifully for the miracle working God!
To God be the glory, I think we have to hear from you before you leave.
Before you were doubting, you never believed that this man was from God
but after your conviction in the dream, what is your opinion of the prophet
and also, what is your advice for all and sundry?
This is what I will say.
The Bible says that man looks at the outward appearance but God looks at the heart.
God knows everything about everybody.
Instead of just picking words from here and there and making up your mind about people,
why don't you just go to God?
Because if we are real Christians, we should go to God before we judge anybody,
or before we say this is not that or this is not a man of God.
I would advise everybody to just seek God in every situation.
And make sure that your mind when it is made up is from God and His opinion about people.
That's what I would say.
Thank you very much for that word of advice. Let's also hear a word of advice from your wife.
With all you have experienced, having been delivered from depression and suicidal thoughts,
what word of advice do you have for everyone?
I would advise to not seek help from people like doctors or therapists or rehabilitation.
I would say, just seek God.
Like my husband said, God sees everything. He sees the deep things. God sees the outer things.
Most of the problems we face have a spiritual force behind them.
So, if you don't deal with it spiritually, you are not going to find the solution.
So, don't seek physical help from doctors or a rehab for something that is spiritual.
You have to go to God because God is the Deliverer.
God can touch you, He can heal you. He healed me and God is not a respecter of persons.
He loves you. After all, it is out of love that He will heal you.
So seek God and don't seek man. Seek God alone for everything and anything.
To God be the glory.
We believe you are trying to make us understand that we serve the God of nature
and medicine is from nature.
Doctors treat while Jesus Christ heals.
And you are telling us that if it comes to spiritual matters, we should seek the face of God.
Yes.
To God be the glory.
Let's put our hands together beautifully for the miracle working God.
Let's hear briefly from your brother-in-law. He may also have some things to contribute.
Could you just introduce yourself to us and tell us what you have to say about your sister's life.
Good Morning Church!
My name is Minor Requeno. This is my sister, Thania and my brother-in-law, Akeem
and my sister in Christ, Elena.
This is our first time in Africa and we are just really excited to be here because
we know that everything that has been going on is from God.
We actually came a little bit unprepared but God has come through the whole way.
I want to thank T.B. Joshua for being a true man of God.
In America and all over the world, there are a lot of false teachers, pastors and prophets.
But being here for a week and witnessing him and listening to him, I can tell the whole world that
that this is a man of God.
To God be the glory and what can you say about your sister, since she has been delivered?
In my family, I was the first one who got saved and she was the second one.
I witnessed her salvation. She was just like a glowing beam.
Everybody could testify that she was full of joy.
Gradually though, it started to diminish and go down a little bit.
Akeem was going through hard times, I was going through hard times, with Elena and my sister,
we all decided to come over here seeking something from the Lord through T.B. Joshua.
So when he pointed that out in my sister, I knew that it was God, especially seeing her on the ground.
I knew it was the Lord.
Ever since then, we are all just really excited and we're just taking that blessing by force; we really are.
Let's put our hands together beautifully for the miracle working God!
Finally, what is your word of advice to everyone?
I would say just like everyone else is saying to open up our hearts.
Seek the Lord from a true heart and from the bottom of your hearts
because like they said, He searches the depths of our hearts and we can't fool Him.
So, if we can just talk to Him and go to Him from the bottom of our hearts,
I think He will answer us and He will see us through.
Thank you. Let's finally listen to our sister.
Emmanuel!
My name is Elena De la Cruz and I'm from the United States.
This is my sister in Christ, Thania with baby Caleb, Akeem, Minor - my brothers and sisters in Christ.
I didn't even know T.B. Joshua existed. I had no clue.
I was always skeptical on internet preachers and pastors because there are a lot of fake ones out there.
When they were telling me some of their testimonies and dreams
and stuff they experienced with T.B. Joshua and who he was,
I just trusted in God.
I prayed to the Lord and asked if He wanted me to come here to Africa because this is my first time.
And He gave me a vision of us coming.
So I said, 'OK Lord - Your will, not mine'.
It's faith that brought us all here. It's faith that broke barriers where most people might have been scared to even come.
And its faith, it's God, Jesus Christ, the Holy Spirit that delivered my sister.
I had no idea she was depressed; I had no idea she had suicidal thoughts
but that's a wicked demonic spirit.
Just trusting in God for deliverance, not in people or psychotherapists or what he, she or it says.
Just the Lord Jesus Christ - that gives you true deliverance.
To sit back and watch T.B. Joshua and his ministry, I feel like its a modern-day of what we read in the Bible.
It gives us so much hope, that the Bible is alive today.
It's such a beautiful thing to see all of this and everybody coming together
for the ministry to really deliver people, so people can be set free, so those chains can be broken,
so my sister can continue growing in the Lord, so her joy can be reignited and she can continue
spreading God's Word everywhere she goes and planting seeds.
Even her testimony is going to set souls free and give other people hope.
I'm so thankful to be along for the ride and to witness all of this.
It's a blessing; I give God all the glory.
Amen.
Let's put our hands together beautifully for the miracle working God!
Briefly before you go, having experienced the goodness of the Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ
through His able servant, Prophet T.B. Joshua,
what word of advice do you have for all who are listening to you?
Trust God. Read His Word on a regular basis, love, love, love.
It's very important to be in the spirit.
One thing I learnt from T.B. Joshua is to constantly pray in the spirit.
I didn't know you could do that.
Instead of having negative thoughts, etc. constantly stay in the spirit and pray in the spirit
before you go to bed, in the spirit.
Be in the spirit and know that the Holy Spirit in you can do all things.
Jesus Christ's death, burial and resurrection is just love. I love it.
I give Him all the glory.
Let's clap for wonderful Jesus!
Yes, it's been awesome.
As far as this family is concerned, it is a clear proof that everyone is going home hale and hearty
and with the goodness of the Lord
And I believe that when you return to the United States of America, you will continue to share your testimony with all who care to listen.
We also want to admonish you by letting you know that
you have been healed, delivered and blessed through the Word of God.
Make sure you go back and make His Word the standard for your lives.
And always have it at the back of your minds that better is not good enough, the best is always yet to come!
Let's put our hands together beautifully for the miracle working God!